# Bryan Stevens

b.stevens.photo@gmail.com github.com/bryanstevens314 linkedin.com/in/bryan-stevens314

I've had a love for everything tech for as long as I can remember, I realized early that the only way to succeed in such a demanding field was to stand on the shoulders of giants and learn from the best. With that has come a simple philosophy that has pulled me through life, that if you touch something you do it to the best of your ability, period. No excuses, no run around; you do the research, you put in the hours and you deliver the best product possible.

### **Experience**

#### **VuSpex - Software Engineer**

May 2020 - Present

- Demonstrated expertise in translating client specific needs into easy to understand software solutions
- Proficiently troubleshot simple and complex technological issues across varying tech stacks
- Utilized software engineering expertise to develop products throughout the software lifecycle

#### Metova - Lead React Native Engineer - Short Term Contract

**January 2022 – June 2022** 

- Oversaw a team of 3 to develop and thoroughly test a React Native module
- Focused on development and providing mentorship/ coaching to the teams junior developers
- Reviewed code and conducted testing

#### **Memo - Lead React Native Engineer - Short Term Contract**

September 2020 – December 2020

- Orchestrated the initial release of the Memo app to the iOS App Store
- Implemented push notifications on android and iOS devices
- Modified JSX, Javascript and styling to give the mobile app a facelift

#### StreamGuys - Junior Software Developer

**September 2019 – May 2020** 

- Modified HTML, Javascript and css to optimize page performance
- Documented all supported systems to effectively train new and existing customers
- Provided prompt solutions and proactive troubleshooting to resolve subtle and complex issues

## **Projects**

- (2021) <u>VuSpex GO: React Native OpenTok Geolocation Services:</u> Developed as a cross platform, single code base solution to replace VuSpex' existing iOS & android mobile apps. The app leverages various technologies from webRTC to gps allowing contractors, field agents, and permit applicants to conduct virtual inspections, create field reports to send to the inspector, and schedule face-to-face or virtual inspections.
- (2020) <u>ELevel+: React Native React N React Native Bluetooth LE:</u> Developed by myself and 2 others as part of a contract; the app connects and communicates with AccuAir's bluetooth module to receive, display and update real time height and position indicators as well as a handful of diagnostic feedback. Core to the app is this ability to update the 4 pieces of AccuAir's firmware stack through a chunked OTA update process.
- **(2016)** <u>Bitcoin Faucet: Objective-C:</u> The app utilized multiple ad networks to mediate advertisements; that coupled with persistent timestamps, small amounts of a Bitcoin were dished out to users for viewing ads. The app was live for several months with over 4.2K total downloads and over 230,000 sessions.

#### Education

#### **Fullstack Academy of Code**

October 2018 – February 2019

- Nationally-ranked software engineering bootcamp with a 9% acceptance rate
- Studied Object-Oriented Design, asynchronous programming and software design
- Extensively practiced pair-programming pairing with all other 28 students individually

#### **Technical Skills**

**Advanced**: React, React Native, Javascript, Typescript, Swift, Java, Objective-C, Git, NodeJS **Knowledgeable**: Redux, Jest, SQL, C#, PHP, Angular, AWS